(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T22:53:29.081876",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
[Title: Hakos Baelz 5th Anniversary Stream - Let's Get Extravaganza!!]
Uwah! What's up!
I am Chaos, the end of ends,
Australia's trapped in the cage of ice,
your best friend Baelz Hakos from Hololive English -Promise-!
Witness me!
やったー！
We did it!
Happy five years, everyone!
5年？ヤバくないですか？
Five years? Isn't that crazy?
ちょっとみんな、ヤバいっすね、5年。
Seriously, everyone, five years is insane!
Thank you so much for joining me today for my 5th anniversary stream!
I can't believe it's been five years!
We're also in a very nostalgic place...
いや、ここもね、ちょっと懐かしい場所に来ましたよね。
Yeah, we've come back to a pretty nostalgic place, haven't we?
This is the stage from my 3D debut stream,
and I thought it'd be fitting to return back here for my big fifth!
Yes! Back in the Fun Zone. Back in the Fun Zone!
We're gonna be hanging out with some awesome guests!
I can't believe some of the guests that, um, very graciously agreed to appear today.
Maybe some games, maybe some singing...
And that's not all! As you may or may not already know,
huge announcements with an 'S' are coming your way,
so make sure you stick to the very end!
えっと、目標ですね。5周年お祝いということなんで、
So, today's goal is to celebrate the 5th anniversary,
えっと、ゲストさんも、あの、すごいゲストさんが来てくれてますので、
and we have some really amazing guests joining us,
本当自分も信じられないぐらい、えっと、楽しみにしてます。
so I'm looking forward to it more than I can believe myself.
ちょっとゲームやったりとか、まあ、歌もね、ちょっとある、あるかな？
We'll do some games, and maybe some singing too? I think?
ちょっと分かんないですけど。あと！
I'm not entirely sure, but also!
重大発表もたくさんありますので、
There are plenty of huge announcements too,
最後まで見ててください！
so please watch until the very end!
And please make sure to share your thoughts on the stream using
#BaeBig5th!
BaeBig5th!
I'll be checking all your posts after the stream, so please...
Get to part!
えーと、それと、配信の感想はハッシュタグ
And also, for stream impressions, please use the hashtag...
#BaeBig5th!
を使って、えーと、投稿してください。
...to post them!
配信が終わったら、僕もみんなもね
Once the stream ends, both I and everyone else...
投稿チェックするので
...will check your posts,
たくさんの感想を待ってますよー！
so we'll be waiting for lots of feedback!
お願いします！
Please do so!
おーっ！
Woo!
Without further ado, let's jump right into our first segment.
いこう！
Let's go!
ああ！
Ah!
ベジャ！
Bae-cha!
イェーイ！ハッピーアニバーサリー！
Yay! Happy anniversary!
ハッピー5thアニバーサリー！
Happy 5th anniversary!
セレブレイト、セレブレイト、おめでとう！
Celebrate, celebrate, congratulations!
ベエちゃん！ハッピーフォアユー。
Bae-chan! Happy for you.
I'm so happy I'm with all of my friends today.
え、自己紹介お願いしてもいいですか？
A-And could you all introduce yourselves?
イェーイ！
Yay!
私？
Me?
Okay, okay, okay.
みなさん、it's me! Mori Calliope from Hololive English -Myth-!
Everyone, it's me! Mori Calliope from Hololive English -Myth-!
ハメツはココ、デス、デス、デス、I'm Shinigami, Reaper, Songwriter...
The ruin is here, death, death, death. I'm a Shinigami, reaper, songwriter...
...and also best friend! Who is your best friend?
イェーイ！ベストフレンド！
Yay! Best friend!
イェーイ！
Yay!
えっ、えっ？よしっ！
Eh? Eh? Okay!
I'm Subaru! Oozora Subaru, Hololive JP Second Generation! And...
ベストフレンド？
Best friend?
ベストフレンド！
Best friend!
イェーイ！
Yay!
待って待って、
Wait, wait...
You said, you said "I'm your best friend, Bae." So you're not my best friend, you're her best friend?
いやいや、まあ、ベストフレンド、
No, no, well, best friend...
ベストフレンド、ベストフレンド！
Best friend, best friend!
みんなベストフレンド！
We are all best friends!
あんど、そして！
And, and...
Hi! Good morning, afternoon, evening! Ninomae Ina'nis from Hololive English -Myth-!
I also want to be Bae's best friend!
ベスト、ベストフレンド！
Best, best friend!
イェーイ！さすが！
Yay! As expected!
次！
Next!
こんぴー！ホロライブ4期生、常闇トワ様でーす！
Kon-pi! Hololive 4th Generation, Tokoyami Towa-sama here!
イェーイ！
Yay!
私こそが、えー、ベエのナンバーワンベストフレンドでーす！
I am indeed Bae's number-one best friend!
No, no, no, no!
All of my best friends are here!
え、みんなベスト、嬉しい！
Eh, everyone's my best friend, I'm so happy!
ナンバーワンは誰？
Who's number one?
I will fight you.
このコーナーナンバーワン、
In this corner, number one...
えっ？えっ？ナンバーワン？
Eh? Eh? Number one?
Bae-Gemite!
Bae-Gemite? ベジマイト、ベジマイト。
Bae-Gemite? Vegemite, Vegemite.
ベジマイトだ。
Vegemite.
What is this? What is this?
これ、あの、Bae-Gemiteです。なんと今日ですね、僕の5周年なんで、It's my 5th anniversary,
This is Bae-Gemite. And today is actually my 5th anniversary...
I bring to you, Bae-Gemite Extravaganza Part 1!
え、え？
Eh? Eh?
僕のベジマイト大企画へようこそ！
Welcome to my big Bae-Gemite project!
またきた、ベジマイト！ベジマイト...
Vegemite again! Vegemite...
お前、ベジマイト好きすぎ！
You love Vegemite too much!
はい、えーと、ベジマイト、大、代表なんで、はい。
Yes, well, I'm the big Vegemite representative, yes.
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
なるほどね。
I see.
えーと、まあ一応説明しますが、
Well, I'll explain it for now.
Bae-Gemite... It's inspired by the greatest food of all: Vegemite.
おお！
Oh!
Packed with Vitamin B, it truly is the ultimate spread.
ビックリしすぎ、ビックリしすぎ。
Too much of a surprise, too much of a surprise.
In fact, it wouldn't be an exaggeration to say that everyone in my country grew up eating it.
And today, I'd like all of my guests to experience the true greatness that is Vegemite first-hand.
これはなんとですね、我が国への、誇りである！
This is, incredibly, the pride of my country!
ねぇねぇ、ルック、ルック！ルック、カリズフェイス。
Hey, look, look! Look at Calli's face.
Why?
But why?
Today we have a very special rendition of Bae-Gemite.
Bae-Gemite SHOWDOWN!
SHOWDOWN? Showdown? ゲームをやりたいと思います！はい。
Showdown? Showdown? We're going to play a game! Yes.
はい。
Yes.
Is this to decide the best friend?
ベストフレンド、ベストフレンド、ベストフレンド！
Best friend, best friend, best friend!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
ゲームをやって、
We'll play a game,
and whoever loses will discover that, you know, they might be missing something, you know?
Do you know what it is, Calli? Do you have any idea what they could be missing if they lose?
Uh...
Yeah, that's right!
Nutrition!
もし負けた方がね、栄養が足りないってこと！
If you lose, it means you're lacking nutrition!
おお！なるほど！
Oh, I see!
僕はですね、やっぱりベジマイトで育てられたので、
Because I, after all, was raised on Vegemite...
あの、僕に負けた人がちょっとね、ちょっと栄養を増やして、
...the people who lose to me will need to increase their nutrition a bit...
え、same tall? Same tall?
Eh, same tall? Same tall?
Nearly same tall! Same tall!
いやいやいや、こっちじゃなくて、これですよ、これ！
No, no, no, not this height, it's this!
Oh! Same tall!
なるほどね
I see.
ってことです
That's what it is.
Is everyone ready?
I'm ready! Ready! Are you ready? Are you ready?
Yeah, bring it on. I guess we're ready.
じゃ、The stage of trials, manifest yourselves! Fun Zone!
Now, the stage of trials, manifest yourselves! Fun Zone!
おお！
Oh!
すごーい！何これ？
Amazing! What is this?
I didn't know you could do that. なんか急に出てきてるやん。
I didn't know you could do that. It just suddenly appeared!
そう、バカの力です、これが。
Yes, this is the power of stupidity.
おお、すごい。レース？コース？
Oh, amazing. A race? A course?
So! The game we're playing today is... the Ultimate Tricycle Race!
Tricycle! 三輪車？
Tricycle! Tricycle?
三輪車レース！ってことです！
Tricycle race! That's what it is!
The rules are very simple. We'll all ride a tricycle and complete two laps around the course we've set up here in the Fun Zone.
And the challenge is to see who can beat my time. 僕より早ければ、あの、勝ちって感じです。
And the challenge is to see who can beat my time. If you're faster than me, you win.
おお、なるほどね。
Oh, I see.
自分らは走らなくていいってことね？
So we don't have to run ourselves?
あ、まあ、うん。
Ah, well, yeah.
Wait, so if we all win...
No one... まあ、一応、うん。
No one... Well, I guess so, yeah.
そうですね。
That's right.
If you win! If you win! If you win!
ということで、ちょっとさっそく始めたいと思いますが、準備はいいですか？
So, I'd like to get started right away, are you ready?
Ok! Everyone ready?
じゃ、先輩お二方、お願いしたいと思います！
Well, I'll have the two seniors go first!
来い、トワ！
Come on, Towa!
三輪車、来い！
Come on, tricycle!
これ、ブーン！
This goes "vroom"!
Ok, ladies, ladies, ladies, ladies.
Ok, ok! Boom!
[大空スバル] トワには負けねえ。俺が勝つ。
[Oozora Subaru] I won't lose to Towa. I'm going to win.
[常闇トワ] スバルのことは眼中にありません。自分との闘いです。
[Tokoyami Towa] Subaru is not even on my radar. This is a battle with myself.
ジャンケンしたいです。Ah, so, ok. They're going to do...
I want to play rock-paper-scissors. Ah, so, ok. They're going to do...
内側が有利なんじゃないかなと。
Because the inside lane is probably advantageous.
They're going to do rock-paper-scissors to find out who gets to ride on the inside. では、どうぞ！
They're going to do rock-paper-scissors to find out who gets to ride on the inside. Ready, go!
Rock, Paper, Scissors, Shoot!
うわあ！やったあ！
Whoa! Yes!
Nice! Nice, Subaru.
じゃ、トワ様が内側ですね。
So, Towa-sama gets the inside lane.
そういうことですね。
That's right.
じゃ、お二人、お二人からちょっと意気込みをお願いします。
Well, could the two of you share your thoughts?
はい。I will win! I will win!
Yes. I will win! I will win!
Win-Subaru! Win-Towa!
We will win!
Win-san!
I will win!
つくって、つくって！痛い！
Hold on, hold on! Ouch!
じゃ、乗ってください。
Well, please get on.
Bae, Bae, Bae. Yes, this battle...
Boom, ok?
Boom, ok! Boom, ok?
Boom, ok. You can interfere with each other if you want. Friendly fire allowed!
Oh, brother. But you just can't, uh, get off your tricycle. Ok?
ちょっと、三輪車降りる、降りるのはちょっとダメ。
But getting off, getting off the tricycle is a no-no.
ああ、なるほどね。
Oh, I see.
でも、妨害はオッケーです。
But interference is okay.
妨害オッケー？オッケーです。やばい、妨害される！
Interference okay? Yes, it's okay. Oh no, I'll get interfered with!
Ready? Yes!
じゃ、行くよ！Here we go!
Alright, here we go! Here we go!
Three, two, one, GO!
行け、行け、行け！
Go, go, go!
Subaru has taken the inside!
Oh!
二回目！二回目！2 lap!
Second lap! Second lap! 2nd lap!
Go, go! Oh no, oh no!
Subaru is at the finish line!
行け、トワ様！行け、行け！
Go, Towa-sama! Go, go!
Yeah!
おめでとう、トワ様！Congratulations!
Congratulations, Towa-sama! Congratulations!
I'm a win-san. I'm a win-san. I'm a win-san.
I'm the winner-san. I'm the winner-san. I'm the winner-san.
Well, technically it wasn't just a battle between them. 一応、あの、タイムアタックなんで、ちょっと後で... タイムアタックなんです。
Well, technically it wasn't just a battle between them. This is a time attack, so later... It's a time attack.
[森カリオペ] I feel really well prepared for this race. You know, I'm a four-times champ of the Underworld University Tricycle Marathon. Yearly...
[Mori Calliope] I feel really well prepared for this race. You know, I'm a four-times champ of the Underworld University Tricycle Marathon. Yearly...
[一伊那爾栖] Win or lose, I get to eat Bae's cookie. Yeah.
[Ninomae Ina'nis] Win or lose, I get to eat Bae's cookie. Yeah.
Alrighty! Seems like Calli and Ina are all set. Are you two feeling confident?
Yeah! Oh! ごめん、ごめん、ごめん、ちっちゃいね。イナちゃんちっちゃい。
Yeah! Oh! Sorry, sorry, sorry, you're so small. Ina-chan is tiny.
ちっちゃい、ちっちゃい。Yeah, even if we lose, we'd never fight.
Tiny, tiny. Yeah, even if we lose, we'd never fight.
You guys ready? Can we get a, a one comment from the both of you, please?
あたし、勝つ。勝つ？ It's not, it's not as funny. 勝つさん。
I will win. Win? It's not, it's not as funny. Winner-san.
かつ！かつ！カツさんです！
Katsu! Katsu! It's Katsu-san!
Yeah, カツ！モリさんとカツ。
Yeah, Katsu! Mori-san and Katsu.
Ina is hungry...
お腹空いた！カツを食え！
Hungry! Eat some katsu!
カツ丼？カツ？何でカツ？
Katsudon? Katsu? Why katsu?
カツオ？カツ丼？カツオ？カツ丼、カツオ、カツ。
Katsuo? Katsudon? Katsuo? Katsudon, Katsuo, katsu.
カツ丼。カツ丼。
Katsudon. Katsudon.
やばい、止めて、止めて！まだ準備できてない！
Oh no, stop, stop! I'm not ready yet!
準備オッケーですか？始めないでくださいね！
Are you ready? Please don't start yet!
We gotta decide who's on the inner and who's on the outer. That's right.
Outside is apparently stronger, so whoever wins gets the outside. Yes.
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot! Ah!
カリは外側。I got a feeling Ina is still gonna win this one.
Calli is on the outside. I got a feeling Ina is still gonna win this one.
This position is best. No, it's not.
I don't know, I got a bad feeling about this one. Ready!
Alright, you guys ready?! Yeah! Alright, here we go!
Three, two, one, GO!
イナ！イナ！カリ！イナがすごい！
Ina! Ina! Calli! Ina is amazing!
イナ！いけ、いけ、いけ！
Ina! Go, go, go!
Get out of my way!
イナ頑張れ！頑張れ！イナ！Get out of my way!
Go Ina! Hang in there! Ina! Get out of my way!
カリ！
Calli!
ゴール！ゴール！イナ！
Goal! Goal! Ina!
イナ、もう一周！
Ina, one more lap!
No one is allowed to get in front of me! 頑張れ、頑張れ！
No one is allowed to get in front of me! Go, go!
イナ！カリ！
Ina! Calli!
ゴール！ゴール！
Goal! Goal!
ゴール！ゴール！ゴール！
Goal! Goal! Goal!
I haven't had this much exercise in 2 years. 筋肉痛。
I haven't had this much exercise in 2 years. My muscles hurt.
イナ、大丈夫？イナは大丈夫？
Ina, are you okay? Is Ina okay?
Are you okay? Are you okay? 大丈夫。イナは死んだ。
Are you okay? Are you okay? I'm okay. Ina is dead.
イナは大丈夫。大丈夫、大丈夫。
Ina is okay. It's okay, it's okay.
Wow, with the four of them completing the race, I think we should announce their times...
...before I try... it...
ま、４人終わったんで、タイムを発表したいと思います。
Well, since the four of them are done, let's announce the times.
レッツゴー！おお！じゃあ、最初は...
Let's go! Oh! So first up is...
スバル先輩！おお！タイムは何でしょうか？
Subaru-senpai! Wooo! What is her time?
２８.８５秒！おお！速い！すごい！
28.85 seconds! Oh! That's fast! Amazing!
これはいいんじゃない？速い！
Isn't this pretty good? So fast!
じゃあ、次はトワ様！はい。
Next is Towa-sama! Yes.
タイムは、ドカン！３５.６３秒！
Her time is... bam! 35.63 seconds!
おお！これも速い！
Oh! That's also fast!
35.63 seconds. 次は...
35.63 seconds. Next is...
...Mori Calliope! Your time is...
36.72 seconds!
イェーイ！私速い。ここじゃ。
Yeah! I'm fast. Here it is.
I'm fast, I'm fast.
え？速い？なんで？で、最後はイナ！
Eh? Fast? Why? And finally, Ina!
Your time is... ３８.４４！
Your time is... 38.44!
おお！でもさ... 36.72, 38.44...
Oh! But you know... 36.72, 38.44...
でもみんな速くね？
But aren't they all fast?
イナはちょっと遅いね。ベイちゃん、もしかしたらあなたも私たちみたいに遅いかも。
Ina is a little slow... Bae-chan, maybe you're also a little slow like we are.
え？違う？１０秒くらいでお願いしたいところか。
Oh? No? We'd like to ask you for around 10 seconds.
So I have to beat...
...みんな食べれるベイだったら...２８点...
...if I'm a Vegemite-eating Bae... then 28...
...２８秒を切ればいいってことですよね。
...I just have to beat 28 seconds, right?
Be faster than 28 seconds. どこに入るかだね、ベイが。
Be faster than 28 seconds. Let's see where Bae places.
うん。
Yeah.
Well, with that being said, 私の番だ！
Well, with that being said, IT'S MY TURN!
「ベジマイトパワーで驚異のタイムを見せられるか！」
[Can Vegemite power deliver a blazing fast time?!]
ということで、ベイの準備ができたそうです！
And with that, it seems Bae is ready!
やった！レッツゴー！堂々。
Yay! Let's go! So majestic.
だか、一番似合ってるわ。
Seriously, it suits her the best.
なんで？ジャストフィット、ジャストフィット！
Why? It's a perfect fit, perfect fit!
Perfect for you. 普段からだって乗ってるでしょ？
Perfect for you. You ride this on a daily basis, right?
普段乗って...乗ってないわ！
I don't ride... I DO NOT RIDE THIS!
Better than a bicycle. そうでしょ？
Better than a bicycle. I know, right?
どうですか？意気込みをお願いします。
How are you feeling? Tell us your enthusiasm.
いや、もうすべてはベジマイトのためである。僕は勝つ。
Yeah, everything is for the sake of Vegemite. I will win.
おお、ベジマイト。とんでもないわ。
Oh, Vegemite. This is crazy.
ベジマイト好きすぎるな。
She loves Vegemite way too much.
ベジマイトから生まれたんじゃない？
Wasn't she born from Vegemite?
ベジマイト...だからベイ？あ、そういうこと？だからベイ！
Vegemite... That's why she's Bae? Ah, is that it? That's why she's Bae!
だからベイですよ。そういうことね、繋がったね。なるほど。
That's why I'm Bae. So that's why! It all connects now. I see.
どうせ勝つし、大丈夫。めっちゃ勝つや。
I'll win anyway, so it's fine. She's so confident about winning.
そんなこと言ったらさ、トワがさ...あ、すみません。
If you say that, Towa is like... 'Ah, excuse me'.
すみません。通ります。通ってもいいですか？
Excuse me, coming through. May I pass through?
お断り。お断りします！
No way. I refuse!
You can't cross. It's been an accident.
It's been an accident. You have to be escorted.
I'm sorry, you can't cross here. Go home!
Go home! Go home! Go home, Bae!
Go home!
ということで、じゃあ、これで順位決まりますから。
So, this will decide our ranking.
我々、我々のベジマイトにどうなるかっていうのは、これで決まりますから。
What happens to our Vegemite will be decided by this.
はい。準備のほうでいいですか？
Okay, are you ready?
Here we go! Go! Go! Go!
3, 2, 1, Go!
なんか、なんか...
What is...
あ、やばい。
Oh, wait.
なんかマジ必死、必死。
She's really desperate.
やばいやばい、ガチの顔してる。
Oh my god, her face is totally serious.
Serious! シリアス。お尻、お尻！
Serious! Serious! Her butt, her butt!
お尻です！お尻です！
Her butt! Her butt!
速い！速い！
Fast! Fast!
あ、もう一周。
Oh, one more lap.
いけ、いけ、いけ！
Go, go, go!
あとちょっと！
Almost there!
ゴール！
Goal!
速い！速い！
Fast! Fast!
はい。
Yes.
速すぎる！
Too fast!
シュール、速すぎて、ちょっと。
It was so surreal and fast.
速すぎるだろ、今の！
That was way too fast!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
じゃあ、
So,
発表、
to the announcement,
行きますかね！
shall we?
さっきの順番で、どこを足すか！
In the order of our ranking, who gets what added!
僕のタイム、お願いします！
My time, please!
24.92!
全員、ベジマイト食べます！
Everyone eats Vegemite!
Oh, she's excited about that.
お調子者すぎる、マジで！やばい！
She's way too cocky, seriously! Crazy!
We're going to prepare...
not a punishment, it's a prize!
みんなも心の優勝なんで、これはプレゼントです。
Everyone is a winner in our hearts, so this is a present.
なんか言ってる。
She's saying something.
いいように言ってるだけ。
She's just putting a good spin on it.
なんか言ってる。
She's saying something.
なので、みんなちょっと待ってね。 We are going to get the place prepared...
So, everyone, please wait a bit. We are going to get the place prepared...
to taste some Vegemite!
Let's go!
ベジマイト、食べます！
We're eating Vegemite!
Wow! The dish is ready! You know...
When I first had these four enter,
I knew from the get-go they were lacking nutrition.
やっぱりね、この4人が入った瞬間にもう、
After all, the moment these four entered,
分かってました。
I already knew.
What are you talking about?
栄養が足りてない！栄養が足りてない！
They lack nutrition! They lack nutrition!
なので、こちらを準備しております。
So, we have prepared this.
You know everyone is lacking nutrition. And what is the most important meal of the day?
That's right, breakfast!
朝ご飯は1番大事な食事なんで、
Breakfast is the most important meal,
今日は皆さまに栄養たっぷり
so today I have prepared a highly nutritious
朝ご飯を用意しております。
breakfast for everyone.
朝ご飯...
Breakfast...
デリシャスなんですか？
Is it delicious?
A very delicious dish! Very delicious!
ベリーデリシャス。
Very delicious.
You can take off your lids! Open!
We will... じゃあ、1つずつご紹介させてください。
We will... So, let us introduce them one by one.
まずですね、あの、生ベジマイトありますね。
First, we have raw Vegemite.
これは後でね、あの、トワ様と、
Later on, Towa-sama and...
え、イナは食べたことないんで、
well, Ina has never eaten it,
1回ちょっとね、生で。
so they'll try it raw first.
味見でね、ちょっとだけ。
Just a little taste.
生ベジマイト。あ、ぜひ。あの、これはもう、健康的な朝ご飯を用意しております。
Raw Vegemite, yes. We have prepared a healthy breakfast.
まずはね、パン！
First, bread!
パンにベジマイトを塗っております。
We have Vegemite spread on bread.
これはまあ、オーストラリアの定番の朝ご飯。
This is a very traditional Australian breakfast.
This is a very traditional breakfast with bread and Vegemite.
で、次参ります。味噌汁でございます。
Next up, we have miso soup.
When we speak of Japanese breakfast, we think of miso soup.
味噌汁ですね。あの、朝ご飯といえば。まあ、本当に豪華！
Miso soup, speaking of breakfast. Truly luxurious!
朝ご飯といえば、お寿司ですね！
Speaking of breakfast, sushi!
朝から食わねえよ、お寿司！
We don't eat sushi for breakfast!
I just need someone to agree with me that Vegemite and sushi is amazing.
ちょっとね、認めてほしくて。お寿司のベジマイト、マジで似合うんで。
I want you to admit it. Vegemite actually goes great with sushi.
本当に？
Really?
で、どこにつけたの？ベジマイト。
So, where did you put the Vegemite?
ワサビみたいに、ちょっと裏につけて。
Just on the back, like wasabi.
ええ、ヤバい！
Ugh, crazy!
ワサビの代わりに、ちょっと。
Instead of wasabi, just a little.
なんかこれ、オープンした瞬間から、なんか鼻がぐじゅぐじゅしてきたんだけど、大丈夫？
The moment we opened this, my nose started tickling. Is this safe?
なので、ちょっと、トワ様とイナは、あの、ベジマイト初なんで。
So, since Towa-sama and Ina are trying Vegemite for the first time...
ちょっと、生で。
try it raw.
Is it going to get rid of the taste of any other food? Try, just a little bit, have a little courage.
All right.
いただきます。 Try it! Try it!
Let's eat. Try it! Try it!
Okay, Towa-sama first. Oh, she's going for it.
ですか？ / え？普通。
Is it? / Huh? Normal.
え？めっちゃいい顔した。
Huh? That was a great face.
まぁ、いけなくはない。
Well, it's not impossible to eat.
ちょっと多すぎな。さすがでございます。
A bit too much, though. Truly impressive.
いけなくはない。いけなくはない、なるほどですね。
"Not impossible." Not impossible, I see.
いけなくはない。はい、オッケーです。じゃあ、次。
Not impossible. Okay, let's move to the next one.
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
ドン・スケアリー！恐れるな！
Don't be scary! Don't fear!
Don't scary, don't scary, don't scary.
It's good, it tastes so good. / Okay.
みそ、みそ、みそ。行きます。
Miso, miso, miso. Here I go.
頑張ってよ！
Good luck!
行きます。
Here I go.
It's not that bad.
See? Of course. Not that bad.
Pretty good. / Equals...
Not that bad equals pretty good.
美味しいでしょ？ / うん、悪くない。
It's good, right? / Yeah, not bad.
悪くない！ / 悪くない！いける。
Not bad! / Not bad! You can eat it.
But would you choose to eat it?
If I had absolutely no other side dishes and only a bowl of rice... possibly.
じゃあ、ちょっとみんなの朝ごはんタイム行きますか？じゃあ、最初はパンでお願いします。
Then, shall we move on to breakfast? Let's start with bread, please.
オッケー。 / いただきます。
Okay. / Let's eat.
パンで！ / はい。
With bread! / Yes.
いただきます。
Let's eat.
It's good with bread. / See!
美味しいでしょ？美味しいですよね。
It's good, right? It tastes good, doesn't it?
You need bread though, or something.
うん、good.
Yeah, good.
See!
うん...
Yeah...
トースト、トースト...
Toast, toast...
This breakfast, enjoy.
しょっぱ、しょっぱい。
Salty, salty.
It is pretty salty.
Yeah, it is pretty salty.
美味しいですよね？ほら、ほら。ほら、全然バツじゃない。
But it's delicious, right? See, see. See, it's not bad at all.
ちょっと味が濃い。 / 味が濃いですね。まぁ、そうですね。
The taste is a bit strong. / It is strong. Well, that's true.
パン食った後に、ちょっと飲みたいじゃないですか。
After eating bread, you want something to drink, right?
飲みたい、飲みたい。
I want to drink, I want to drink.
じゃあ、次はお味噌汁お願いします。
Then, next up is miso soup, please.
お味噌汁。 / お味噌汁。
Miso soup. / Miso soup.
Three stars out of...
Out of ten? Out of ten! Out of five...
お味噌汁、お味噌汁。
Miso soup, miso soup.
Miso soup. / Miso soup.
お味噌汁美味しい。
Miso soup is delicious.
おお！Good!
Oh! Good!
お味噌汁美味しい。 / Very good, very good!
Miso soup is delicious. / Very good, very good!
Wow, yummy item. Mm.
Don't get mad, don't get mad, don't get mad at me.
Yo, she's gonna kill me.
I don't taste it in them. But somehow, it doesn't...
普通のお味噌。 / うん、普通の味噌汁。
It's just normal miso. / Yeah, normal miso soup.
いや、美味しい、美味しい！ / 美味しい。
No, it's good, it's good! / It's good.
これ合格です。 / 合格？ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
This is a pass. / A pass? Thank you! Thank you!
最後ちょっと本当に...
Lastly, this is really...
最後きつ。 / いや、魚の方でちょっと食べてほしいんですけど。
The last one is tough. / Well, I want you to try it with fish.
いや、これ嫌だ！ / いや、美味しい、絶対美味しい！
No, I hate this! / No, it's definitely good!
Calli. いただきます。
Calli. I'll eat.
You don't have to dip it in soy sauce.
たまごで。
I'll take the egg.
That's not the fish!
Tamago.
Eat the salmon, eat the salmon!
いやだ、I want tamago sushi.
No way, I want tamago sushi.
もう醤油につけなくて大丈夫です。
You don't need to dip it in soy sauce.
醤油につけなくていいの？！ / いや、しょっぱいな。
We don't need to dip it in soy sauce?! / Well, it's already salty.
どう？ / Is it good?
How is it? / Is it good?
It's fine. / Oh!
次、次、次誰行きます？はい、はい。
Next, next, who is next? Yes, yes.
うわあ！
Whoa!
いただきます。 / はい。
I will eat. / Yes.
ああ...
Ah...
まぁ、微妙。
Well, it's subtle.
いや、普通。
No, it's normal.
え？普通？ / いや、違う違う違う。美味しい、美味しい。
Eh? Normal? / No, no, no. It's good, it's good.
最初、美味しいの顔してた。
You had a 'delicious' face at first.
Two stars. / Two stars. / Right, two stars.
では、いただきます。
Well, I will eat.
そうだよね、わかるよ。
Right, I get it.
ちょっと。 / I think so too, I think so too.
A bit... / I think so too, I think so too.
なんか、このBGMとタイミングが...
Somehow, this BGM matches the timing...
いやいやいや。No Vegemiteじゃない？なんか。
No, wait. Isn't there no Vegemite? Somehow.
ベジマイトなくない？
Isn't there no Vegemite?
うん、ベジマイトない。
Yeah, no Vegemite.
There is no Vegemite. え、だから、put on. On Vegemite.
There is no Vegemite. Ah, so, put on... on Vegemite.
でも、今中に入れたよ。
But we put it inside just now.
中だとわからないんだって。 / わからない。
If it's inside, we can't tell. / We can't tell.
ね、ちゃんとつけた方がいいと思うけど。
Right, I think we should put it on top.
ダイレクト、ダイレクトベジマイトしないと。
Direct, direct Vegemite, we have to do that.
あ、そう、そう。そっち？
Ah, right, right. That one?
そうそうそうそう。 / オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Yes, yes, yes, yes. / Okay, okay, okay.
じゃあ、いか。
Then, squid.
そうすると星2になるよ。 / いか、行きます。
If you do that, it'll become two stars. / Squid, I'm going.
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
She is so cute! Why?
いかもいいかな。
Maybe squid is okay.
大丈夫っすよ。
It's fine.
なに、なにがいいですか？なんかどうしました？
What, what is good? What's wrong?
うん。
Yeah.
お寿司を買って、冷蔵庫にちょっと入れて...
I bought sushi, and in the fridge... I put it in a bit...
撮ったの忘れて
I forgot we took it.
寿司なのに、食べる感じの
Even though it's sushi, it feels like eating...
いやいやいや、味がする。
No, no, no, it has a taste.
それさ、寿司派やん。
Wait, you're Team Sushi, right?
寿司派やん、寿司派！
You're definitely on Team Sushi!
寿司や！
It is sushi!
でもその... やばい、ベジマイトの匂いが。
But that... Oh no, the smell of Vegemite.
あ、結構美味しいな。
Ah, it's actually pretty delicious.
やったー！
Yay!
1つ、2つ、3つ星。
One, two, three stars.
How many stars?
How many?
うーん...
Hmmm...
5！
Five!
Five stars!
Five out of five!
Out of ten? No, five out of five!
Five out of five, right?
よっしゃー！
Alright!
僕が食べたときめっちゃ美味しかったんすけど、なんで？
It tasted really good when I ate it, so why?
ハコスの舌はクレイジーなのかな？
Maybe Hakos's tongue is crazy?
うーん、そんな... まあ。
Well, maybe...
まあ、味は一旦よしとして...
Well, setting the taste aside for now...
栄養はたっぷり入ってます！
It's packed with nutrients!
Nutrition! And I think...
ちょっとね、前にいきましょうか。
Let's move to the front a bit.
ちょっと、みんな前に。
Everyone, step forward.
Thank you for the food!
You're welcome! ごちそうさまでした！
You're welcome! Thanks for the meal!
いや、ちょっとね。
Well, next...
どっちが良い？
Which is better?
おーけー！
Okay!
ほらほら、栄養、栄養のせいか...
Look, look, is it because of the nutrition?
栄養ダンス？
Nutrition dance?
本当に楽しかったです！ありがとうございました！
It was really fun! Thank you so much!
Thank you!
I'm so happy that all my, you know, lovely friends...
could join me in best... best friends...
join me in celebrating my fifth anniversary.
And, you know, not only I get to celebrate it with Vegemite,
but also with these lovely ladies.
And also, I have a huge announcement.
おっと！告知？
Oh! An announcement?
告知、お知らせがあります！
I have a big announcement!
Big announcement!
Big announcement has...
びっぐなお知らせが来ましたので、ちょっとみんな一緒に
Since a big announcement has arrived, everyone, together...
あの、どうぞ！って言ってくれますか？
could you say "Here you go!"?
If you're ready, it's time for the first announcement!
Please take a look at this! Dozo!
どうぞー！
Here you go!
[汝の心を動かすものはなんだ？]
[What moves thy heart?]
[真の望みはなんだ？]
[What is thy true desire?]
[失われた王冠は影の中で待つ]
[The fallen crown awaits from the shadows...]
[彼女の刻は来た]
[Her time has come,]
[何人もその支配を拒むことはできない]
[No one will ever question her rule again.]
I'll run the world
Don't be upset, it ain't a defeat if you win
満ち足りないパワー おねだりするわ
Unsatisfied power, begging for it
Give me more, I need more, oh you'll be begging on the floor
自分次第 衝撃与え 動くよショータイム
It's up to you, delivering an impact, it's showtime
[魂を捧げ、そして平伏せ] Give me some more
[Offer up thy soul and kneel.] Give me some more
[彼女の意志に跪く者たちよ...] Just a little bit more
[For those who bow before her will...] Just a little bit more
[彼女の軌跡を目撃せよ]
[WITNESS HER LEGACY!]
I finally did it!
I can't believe it guys, I did it!
I am finally holding my very own solo concert!
ソロライブ決定です！やったー！
My solo concert is officially decided! Yay!
I'm so happy!
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
It's gonna be happening on December 1st of this year,
and the venue is none other than Kanadevia Hall in Tokyo!
えっと、なんと12月1日決定されました、ソロライブです！
And, my solo concert is confirmed for December 1st!
えっと、東京のKanadevia Hallで開催決定です！
It's officially being held at Kanadevia Hall in Tokyo!
もう決定、決定ですよ、みんな！やったー！
It's decided, it's decided everyone! Yay!
えっと、ライブのタイトルは『REGALIA』。
And, the title of the concert is "REGALIA".
This is the title of the live, REGALIA.
I chose this title because I wanted this live to, you know, become...
...symbol of my journey so far, and hopefully, a symbol for what is yet to come for Hakos Baelz, you know.
えっと、ま、今回のライブタイトルは「REGALIA」です。
Um, well, the title of this live concert is "REGALIA".
このライブは、ね、僕のこれまでの活動を象徴するぞっていう意思を込めて、このタイトルにしました。
I chose this title with the intention of making this live concert a symbol of my activities so far.
えっと、チケットやグッズの情報は後日発表しますので、もう少々お待ちください。
Um, information about tickets and merchandise will be announced at a later date, so please wait a little longer.
Tickets and goods will be announced later on, so please get hyped!
I did it! I did it!
And there's more!
In celebration of my first ever solo live, I am so happy to announce that my second album, "Mirror Mirror", is on its way!
Pre-orders will open today from 9:00 PM JST on the Hololive Production Official Shop.
そして、えっと、ま、ライブに向けてセカンドアルバムも、あの、出ます！
And, um, well, in preparation for the live concert, my second album is also, you know, coming out!
「Mirror Mirror」というリリースが、あの、決定しました！
The release of "Mirror Mirror" has been decided!
えっと、日本時間で今日23日の夜9時から、えっと、ホロライブプロダクション公式ショップで、あの、ま、受注開始されます！
Um, pre-orders will open on the Hololive Production Official Shop starting tonight at 9:00 PM JST on the 23rd!
ありがとうございます。本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you. Thank you so much.
This album is so special to me. It...
includes many songs. Um, actually, I wrote the lyrics of most of the songs on this album,
with the theme of reflection, facing oneself, and this album was a project where I pushed myself to explore even more ways to express myself as an artist.
えっとなんとですね、今回のアルバムの曲はだいたい全部、歌詞の方は自分で書いてました。
And actually, I wrote the lyrics for almost all the songs on this album myself.
えっと、ま、「リフレクション、自己との向き合い」っていうテーマの下で、ま、アーティストとしてのさらなる表現力を、えっと、追求した作品となってます。
With the theme of reflection and facing oneself, this is a work where I wanted to pursue further expressiveness as an artist.
Uh, it also comes with a lot of, uh, album bonuses.
Uh, it also comes with a lot of album bonuses.
You'll receive a special message letter with my signature, an original mirror sticker, and an artbook-style lyric booklet. I'll be signing every single one of them, so please get it!
あとね、アルバム、え、購入特典もあります。サイン入りのスペシャルメッセージ、日本語版も、英語版もあります。
Also, there are album purchase bonuses. There's a signed special message, available in both Japanese and English versions.
オリジナルミラーステッカーもあります。アートブック型の歌詞カードもあります。
An original mirror sticker is also included. There is also an artbook-style lyric card.
え、もう買ってくれ、て、くれたみんなも、サイン、サインをしますので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
Um, for everyone who purchases it, I will be signing them, so please check it out.
Ah, you can check the shop directly from YouTube, um, and both the album shipment and the digital release...
...are scheduled for November 2nd JST. So get hyped!
Stay tuned, there's a lot yet to come.
えっと、ショ、あ、YouTubeからショップ、え、アクセスできるので、ぜひチェックしてください。
Um, you can access the shop directly from YouTube, so please check it out.
また発送と、え、デジタルリリースは11月2日を予定しております。楽しみにしててください。
Also, shipment and the digital release are scheduled for November 2nd. Please look forward to it!
そして！そして！そして！
And! And! And!
Ah, I may have mentioned before that there is a new song releasing today, and that is right!
Right after this stream, the music video for "I found me", which is a very, very special song that is actually the first song I ever wrote from scratch, will be releasing, will be premiering after this stream.
えっと、この配信が終わったとき、ちょっと、あの、アルバムからの一曲「I found me」のMVが公開します。
Um, when this stream ends, the MV for "I found me", a song from the album, will be released.
この曲は、僕にとってめっちゃ大事な曲なんで、そして、初めて一から書いた曲なんで、あの、歌詞の方にね。なのでぜひぜひ、プレミア、公開、よろしくお願いします。
This song is very important to me, and it's the first time I've written lyrics from scratch. So please check out the premiere!
The MV will be the opening video for my segment during YouTube Music Weekend!
Ta-da!
It's a lot! I'm so happy! My fifth anniversary and I get to be a part of YouTube Music Weekend. Um, so it will be the opening video for my section, which starts at 1:15 PM JST. So make sure you check it out!
このMVは、このあと13時15分からスタートする「YouTube Music Weekend」で、僕のオープニングパートにもなってるので、ぜひぜひ、これも、チェックしてください！
This MV is also the opening part for my segment in the YouTube Music Weekend starting at 1:15 PM JST, so please check it out as well!
Ah! I did it!
Ah, that was a lot of announcements.
Are you guys, are you guys proud of me? I hope so. You guys know why I've been so busy now! I've been busy. I've been...
already doing a lot of prep for this amazing event that's happening, and I'll be sharing more details about the concert at a later date, so I really hope you look forward to it.
えっと、ま、最近ちょっと僕ね、あの、疲れてるプラスめっちゃ忙しくなった理由もこれになりますので、本当に頑張りますので、あの、楽しみにしててください！
Um, well, this is also the reason why I've been a bit tired and extremely busy lately, so I'll do my absolute best! Please look forward to it!
All right, with that being said, I think it's time to move on to the next segment.
ちょっと次のコーナーに、行きたいと思います！
I'd like to move on to the next segment!
Welcome to...
ベージマイトコンコクション！イェーイ！
Bae-gemite Concoctions! Yay!
見てる方も I think everyone knows... 一応、自己紹介お願いしていいですか？
For everyone watching... I think everyone knows, but could you please introduce yourselves?
はい！もちろんございます。じゃ、私から。
Yes! Of course. I'll go first then.
ホロスターズの夕刻ロベルです。本日はよろしくお願いいたします。
I'm Yukoku Roberu from Holostars. Thank you for having me today!
なんか不穏な感じがね、しますけど。
そうですね。
It feels a bit ominous, though.
Yes, it does.
はい、怖いです。
Yes, I'm scared.
怖くない、怖くないもんね。そうね。
頑張りたいと思います。よろしくお願いします。
No, I'm not. I'm not scared, right?
I'll do my best. Thank you very much.
よろしくお願いします。そして？
はい。
Thank you! And next?
Yes.
あの、理由も分からず呼び出されて
Um, I was called here without being told why...
仕事だと思って来たら、なんだか不穏なスタジオでした。石川界人です。声優です。よろしくお願いします。
And when I thought it was just a regular job, I ended up in this ominous studio. I'm Ishikawa Kaito, a voice actor. Pleased to meet you.
そんな我々からも、ちょっとベエちゃんに言わなきゃいけないこと、あります。
ありますね。
Actually, we have something we need to tell you too, Bae-chan.
We do.
はい、じゃあ行きましょう。
はい。
All right, let's go.
Yes.
せーの！
One, two...
ソロライブ開催決定、おめでとう！
ありがとうございます！
Congratulations on your solo live concert!
Thank you so much!
すごいことよ！
あ、泣いちゃった。あららら。
That's a huge deal!
Ah, she's crying. Oh dear.
嬉しい。
嬉しい？いや、すごいことよ。おめでとう。
I'm so happy.
Are you happy? It's really amazing. Congratulations.
ありがとうございます。
本当におめでとう。
Thank you very much.
My sincere congratulations.
なんか、一VTuberファンとしてさ、
You know, as a fellow VTuber fan...
ソロライブというのは夢じゃん。
夢ですよね。本当に。
A solo live is like the ultimate dream.
It really is a dream. Truly.
なんかもう、熱いわ！
ありがとうございます。
I'm getting emotional!
Thank you so much.
本当に、素晴らしい本当に。
Truly, it's wonderful. Really.
えーと、今日はね、チャレンジをやりたいと思います。
チャレンジ。チャレンジ。
Well, today, we're going to do a challenge.
A challenge? Yes, a challenge.
Challenge. Today, we've invited these two for a challenge called "The Bae-gemite Concoctions." We've come up with some absolutely outrageous Vegemite concoctions.
Today, we've invited these two for a challenge called "The Bae-gemite Concoctions." We've come up with some absolutely outrageous Vegemite concoctions.
まあ、ロベさん、界人さんはもうベージマイトのことご存知しておりますよね？もちろん。
Well, Robe-san and Kaito-san, you're already familiar with Vegemite, right? Of course.
なんか当たり前のように口にしてるけど、
You say it like it's a completely normal thing, but...
我々にとっては、その、呪詛みたいなもん。
For us, it's basically like a curse.
そう、あの、怖いのよ。結構。
Yeah, it's actually pretty terrifying.
ベージマイトで言ったら、まあ、ロベさんですよね？
そうなの？
Speaking of Vegemite, that's your thing, right, Robe-san?
Is it?
いや、でもね、正直、ベージマイトという道を作ってしまった張本人かもしれん。
そうです。
But honestly, I might be the one who paved this Vegemite path.
Yes, indeed.
ベエちゃんにベージマイトっていうものがあるよって教えてもらって、僕がその実食配信みたいのをするようになったんですよ。
Bae-chan told me about Vegemite, and I ended up doing a tasting stream.
そこから始まったこの地獄は。
そして被害者たちが。
That where this hell began, probably.
And then, the victims...
被害者たちが生まれていった。
The victims started piling up.
そうで、一緒にね、その配信で、食レポみたいな配信したこともあって。
うんうん。
And we once did a tasting review stream together.
Right, right.
で、それ以来なんで、このこいつと対峙するのは、3, 4年ぶりぐらいになります、私は。
So since then, facing off against this thing... It's been about 3 or 4 years for me.
あ、じゃあもう、味も忘れちゃってそうだもんね。
So you've probably forgotten what it tastes like.
ううん、あのね、こびり付いてる。
No, it's burned into my memory.
4年経っても消えない。
言い方。
味の記憶がこびり付いてる。
Even after 4 years, it won't go away.
What a way to put it.
The memory of the taste is stuck there.
うん、だから非常にね、怖さはあるけど、まあでもね、楽しみですよ。
So, yes, I'm very scared, but I'm looking forward to it too.
もっと元気そうに。
Say it with more energy!
楽しみです！イェーイ！すごい楽しみ、食べたい！
I'm looking forward to it! Yay! I can't wait to eat it!
そして、界人さん。ベージマイトエピソードってことあります？
And Kaito-san, do you have any Vegemite episodes?
ああ、ベージマイトエピソードですか？非常に素晴らしいあの、食材ですよね。
Ah, my Vegemite episode? It's a truly wonderful ingredient, isn't it?
もらってましたよね？ベエちゃんから。ホロごえで一緒になった時に、ベエちゃんからありがたいお土産をもらってましたよね。
You got some from Bae-chan, right? When you were on Hologoe together, you received a wonderful souvenir from Bae-chan, right?
ええ。番組収録終了時にね、わざわざ楽屋にご挨拶いただいて、
Yes, after we finished recording, she came to my dressing room to greet me...
素敵なかただなというふうに思って受け取って、「これお土産です」と。
And I thought, "What a polite and wonderful person." So I accepted it and she said, "This is a souvenir."
ありがとうございます。あれですか？なんかお菓子か何かですか？あ、ベージマイトです。
I said, "Thank you. Is it some kind of snack?" And she said, "No, it's Vegemite."
一応、食べましたよ。
I did eat it, for the record.
おお、偉い！
食べました？
ちゃんと食べました。
Wow, how admirable!
Really?
Yes, I ate it properly.
絶対食べてないと思ったもん。
なんて素晴らしい食材なんだろうって。
I was sure you didn't eat it.
I thought, "What a wonderful ingredient."
ありがとうございます！
素晴らしいんだ、やっぱベージマイトというのは。
Thank you so much!
So Vegemite really is amazing after all.
ちょっとね、記憶もね、あんまないと思いますので、ちょっと、先に、生で、食べさせてもらいます。
Since you might not remember it well, I'm going to have you taste it raw first.
I got to refresh their memories on the taste, so we do have Vegemite prepared in front of us.
大丈夫。大丈夫。
I'll be fine. I'll be fine.
いや、大丈夫じゃないです。
あの、大丈夫だよ。
No, you won't be fine.
It's okay.
あの、お願いして、わけじゃなくて、5周年なんで、命令です。食えと。
It's not like I'm asking you nicely. It's my 5th anniversary, so it's an order. Eat it.
ソロライブも決まってるしな。
Well, her solo live is confirmed, after all.
めでたい人の命令じゃ。
そうです。
It's an order from the star of the hour.
Yes, indeed.
あ、怖い！
はい、じゃ、せーの！
Ah, I'm scared!
Okay, one, two...
乾杯！
Cheers!
あ、美味しい。
美味しい！
Ah, delicious.
It's tasty!
うまい。すごい。
Tasty! This is intense.
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
大丈夫な、えっ！もう飲み切っちゃいました！
Wait! He already finished the whole bottle of water!
はい、えー、Ishikawa Kaito has finished one bottle of water. 早いですね。
Yes, Ishikawa Kaito has finished one bottle of water. That was fast.
お水にとても合うな！
This goes so well with water!
あー、幸せ。
Ah, so happy...
大丈夫でしょうか？ちょっと、あの...しんじ先輩の顔がえぐい。
Are you alright? Shinji-senpai's face looks intense...
おおー。
Oh...
泣いてる。
He's crying.
泣いてます？
Are you crying?
ほぼ泣いとる。
He's basically crying.
何で？
Why?
美味しくて。
Because it's delicious.
美味しすぎて？美味しすぎて泣いてる？
Too delicious? Crying because it's too delicious?
美味すぎてね、涙が止まらないね。
It's so delicious, the tears won't stop.
しんご、あの、両端死んでる。両端死んでると思って。
Shingo... I mean, both ends are dead. I think both ends are dead.
両端は死んでると思って。
I think both ends are dead.
はい。はい。
Yes. Yes.
はい、じゃあ説明行きます。えーっと、We have the Bae-gemite Concoctions! So it is a tasting... competition, but also tasting event.
Okay, let's go over the explanation. We have the Bae-gemite Concoctions! So it is a tasting... competition, but also tasting event.
To explain how it works, before today, Roberu-senpai, Shingo-san, and I each came up with an ingredient that we thought would pair well with Vegemite.
And using all of our ideas as inspiration, a professional food coordinator, professional!
え？
Eh?
あ、そう？
Oh, really?
A professional food coordinator has created each dish with great care, and we're going to taste all of them and decide who came up with the best Vegemite concoction.
なるほど、我々が選んだ食材で、プロの方がすごく美味しくベジマイトを使って料理してくださってると。
I see, a professional has made a very delicious dish using Vegemite with the ingredients we chose.
はい！
Yes!
なるほど。それ、信じられるの？
I see. Can we believe that?
いや、信じ...え？いや、でもベジマイト元々美味しいの！
Well, believe... eh? No, but Vegemite is already delicious!
あ、そうだった。ごめんごめんごめん。
Oh, that's right. Sorry, sorry, sorry.
プロだからね！
Because they're a professional!
プロだもんね。ベジマイト美味しいしね。
They are a professional. And Vegemite is delicious.
美味しい！
Delicious!
設定があるから...
Because there's a setting...
なので、美味しいプラス美味しいイコール美味しいじゃないですか。
So, delicious plus delicious equals delicious, right?
あ、そうですね。美味しい。
Ah, yes. Delicious.
美味しい。っていうことで、お互いに何を選んだか全く分かんない。
Delicious. So, we have absolutely no idea what each of us chose.
全く知らない、マジで。
Totally don't know, seriously.
We don't know what the other has chosen, so it's going to be a surprise to us as well.
ま、早速始めようか。
Well, let's start right away.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
いいですよ、始めます。
Sure, let's start.
一旦休憩時間ほしいかな。
I kind of want a break time first.
休憩！？
A break!?
胃の中でベジマイトが大暴れしてるんだわ。
Vegemite is running wild in my stomach.
あ、すごいよね。生きてる、これは。
Ah, it's amazing. It's alive, this is.
まあ、最初にちょっと何を選んだかロベル先輩に聞きたくて。
Well, first I want to ask Roberu-senpai what he chose.
じゃあ、僕からいきますか？最初にお願いします。
Then, shall I go first? First, please.
お願いします！
Please!
わかりました。えーでは、僕が選んだ食材はこちらでございます！
Understood. Well then, the ingredient I chose is this one!
牛タンです！
Beef tongue!
牛タン！おー！
Beef tongue! Oh!
神！牛タンです。で、やっぱりしょっぱいじゃないですか、ベジマイトって。
God! Beef tongue. And after all, Vegemite is salty, right?
で、これはお肉に合うんじゃないかなって思ったんですよ、僕。
And I thought this would go really well with meat.
あー、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
そこで、単純に僕が牛タン食べたかったのもありまして、あのアンケートを書いたときに。
And also, I simply wanted to eat beef tongue when I filled out the survey.
あー、そういうこと。
Ah, I see.
なので今回、牛タンを選ばせていただきました。
So this time, I chose beef tongue.
確かに！
Indeed!
美味しくならないわけがない。
There's no way it won't be delicious.
なるほどですね。美味しいと思います。
I see. I think it'll be delicious.
確かに焼肉系はうまそう。
Indeed, yakiniku-style sounds delicious.
ねー！
Right!
Gyutan, which is beef tongue. It is a yakiniku meat, and the reason he chose it was because, well, meat, Vegemite is salty, would be a good pairing, one would think. なるほどですね！
はい！
Yes!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
素晴らしいでしょ、これ。
Wonderful, right, this?
これをちょっとプロの方にお願いしているので、何が出てくるでしょうか？
Since we've asked a professional to do this, I wonder what will come out?
ドキドキするな、これ。
This makes my heart race.
じゃ、見ていきましょう！お願いします！
Then, let's take a look! Please!
お願いします！
Please!
おおー！うわー！
Ooh! Wow!
うまそうだけど！
It looks delicious, but!
めちゃくちゃ、うまそう！
It looks incredibly delicious!
うまそう！え、ちょっと待って、ベジマイト発見できないですよね、ちょっと。まあ。
Delicious! Eh, wait a minute, we can't find the Vegemite, can we? Well.
え、すごい。
Wow, amazing.
どこか入ってる？
Is it in there somewhere?
これがね、一応「牛タントルティーヤ」。
This is, for now, "Beef Tongue Tortilla".
トルティーヤ！
Tortilla!
トルティーヤ。だそうでございます。
Tortilla. That's what it is.
It's like a tortilla, it's like a wrap!
はいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes.
ま、最近はね、タコスも流行ってますからね。
Well, tacos have been trendy lately too.
ね、流行ってますからね。
Right, they are trendy.
Yeah, it's like this really... いや、ソースめちゃいい匂いするね。
Yeah, it's like this really... No, the sauce smells really good.
ソースをかけたらいいのかな？これは。じゃ、ちょっと食べてみます。
Should we pour the sauce? This. Well, I'll try eating it.
食べてみます！
Let's try eating it!
じゃ、ロベルさん、行っちゃってよ。
Then, Roberu-san, go ahead.
ちゃんとしてるなー。いただきます。ちょっとちゃんとしてる！
It looks so proper. Let's eat. It looks a bit too proper!
お、行ってる行ってる行ってる。
Oh, he's going, he's going.
うん。
Mmh.
お、食べてます、食べてます。じゃ、私もいただきます。
Oh, he's eating, he's eating. Then, I'll have some too.
うん。
Mmh.
お、いい感じだぞ、ロベルさんが。
Oh, Roberu-san looks like he's enjoying it.
うん、うん、うん。
Mmh, mmh, mmh.
ロベっさん、どうよ？
Robes-san, how is it?
いや、あのね...
Well, you see...
うーん！って言っていいですか？
Mmh! Can I say that? Trumpet effect!
うん。
Mmh.
全然美味しいです。
It's totally delicious.
ええー！？
Eeeh!?
あの、ベジマイトがどこにいるか分かんないです。
Um, I don't know where the Vegemite is.
え、それって合ってるの？
Eh, is that right?
分かんないです。
I don't know.
うーん！
Mmh!
え、でも、美味い？
Eh, but is it delicious?
うーん、美味い！
Mmh, delicious!
へえー、美味い。
Huh, delicious.
そっか、今、二人が先に食べてリアクション見てから食べようと思って。
I see, I thought I'd watch you two eat and react first before eating.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
じゃあ、大丈夫そうだね。いただきます。
Then, it seems safe. Let's eat.
こいつ！
This guy!
うーん！うーん！
Mmh! Mmh!
うーん！うっま！
Mmh! Delicious!
え？
Eh?
本当にね、ベジマイトがどこにいるかマジで分からん。
Seriously, I have absolutely no idea where the Vegemite is.
うーん。
Mmh.
で、これ、これはまたプロの方からのアレがあるんですかね？
And this, do we have comments from the professional again?
Salt in the lemon sauce, we replaced that with Vegemite! 天才すぎる！
We replaced the salt in the lemon sauce with Vegemite! It's pure genius!
あ、そう。なるほど。塩味だけを残したんだ。
Oh, I see. So she just kept the saltiness.
いや、でもベジマイトの風味はあるじゃないですか。
But the Vegemite flavor is still there, isn't it?
あ、でも確かに、食べ終わったあとちょっと。
Oh, indeed. After you finish eating, there's a little...
It has like a slight like... It's like a refreshing breeze of Vegemite.
なんか優しい風みたいな。/ 確かにね。
Like a gentle breeze, maybe? / True.
ベジマイトが優しい風になることあるんだね。
I didn't think Vegemite could ever become a gentle breeze.
そうですね。/ ベジマイトだけ食べたら岩で殴られたみたいな衝撃あったけど...
Yeah. / Eating pure Vegemite felt like being hit with a rock, but...
こんな優しい風に調理できるんだね、ベジマイトって。/ ベジマイトは優しいです。
You can actually cook Vegemite to be this gentle of a breeze. / Vegemite is gentle.
すご。これは美味しいですね。/ ね！
Amazing. This is really delicious! / Right?
では続いて、界人さん！
Up next, Kaito-san!
We're gonna move on with Ishikawa Kaito-san's ingredients.
どんなものを選びました？
What kind of ingredient did you choose?
じゃあ、僕が選んだ食材、こちらです！ドン！
Well, here is the ingredient I chose! Bam!
なに？なにですか？
What? What is it?
納豆です！
It's natto!
いやー！ / きたー！
No way! / It's here!
納豆！/ きついっす。
Natto! / That's rough.
あれ、納豆好き？/ ですよね。/ 納豆好きよ。
Wait, do you like natto? / Yes, I do. / I like natto too.
もう癖強には癖強ぶつけたら、こうなんだろう、対消滅みたいにするんじゃないかなと思って。
I thought if we clash strong flavors against each other, they might cancel each other out.
I like the way he thinks! I like the way he thinks! もうめちゃくちゃ素晴らしいと思います。
I like the way he thinks! I like the way he thinks! I think that's absolutely wonderful.
そう、こちらを選ばせていただきました。日本の文化をぶつけてやるぜ！
Yes, that's why I chose it. Time to clash it with Japanese culture!
This is Japanese culture, yes.
Mā, without further ado, what is the professional chef gonna do this time? 見ていきましょう！お願いします！
Well, without further ado, let's see what the professional chef did this time! Here we go!
どうなっちゃうの、納豆は？
What's going to happen to the natto?
おおー！ ええ？
Whoa! / Huh?
なんだこれ？/ どういうこと？/ どういうこと？
What is this? / What does this mean? / What do you mean?
どういうことだ？/ うまそう。/ ええ？何、何、何？
What on earth is this? / It looks delicious. / What is going on?
これ、どういう食べ物？/ え？あの、発酵生春巻き？
What kind of food is this? / Huh? Is that "Fermented Fresh Spring Rolls"?
発酵生春巻き...生春巻きだ！/ なるほど！
Fermented fresh spring rolls... They're spring rolls! / I see!
生春巻き。発酵生春巻きって言葉も初めて聞きましたけど。
Fresh spring rolls. It's my first time hearing "Fermented Fresh Spring Rolls" though.
うわー、めっちゃとろとろしてる！
Whoa, it's so slimy and gooey!
これはもう一口で行くか。/ いっちゃってよ、ベえさん。
I should probably eat this in one bite. / Go for it, Bae-san.
はい、じゃ、つけて。いただきます。
Okay, let me dip it... Here we go.
うわ、めちゃくちゃ... It's so slimy. いただきます。
Whoa, it's incredibly... It's so slimy. Let's eat.
んん... / ん？これ...
Mmm... Huh? This is...
界人さん。/ え？/ 先に言っとく。/ うん。
Kaito-san. / Yeah? / I'll tell you in advance. / Yes?
明確にいる。/ いる？/ いる。
He is definitely in there. / He is? / He is.
やつがいる。
That guy is in there.
（咀嚼音・笑う）
(Chews/laughs)
いるな！
He's there!
いる！
He is in there!
いや、これ、ソースにいるね。/ これソースか。/ うん。
Ah, he is in the sauce. / Oh, is it in the sauce? / Yeah.
あれ、全然味しないですけど。え？
Wait, I don't taste him at all. Huh?
うまい。え？
It's delicious. Wait, what?
え？あれ、調和してる？/ いや、いるよ。納豆に押し勝ってるぐらいまである。
Huh? Wait, is it balanced? / No, he's there. He's almost overpowering the natto.
うん、わかる。相当だ。
Yeah, I get it. Big time.
めっちゃ美味しい。/ うん、美味しい。
It's so delicious. / Yeah, it is.
普通に、発酵同士なので相性がいいとのことのことでございます。
Since they're both fermented foods, they actually go quite well together.
やっぱ塩味があるので、何かのソースにできると、やっぱ塩味なんですね。
Since it has saltiness, using it in a sauce highlights that quality.
納豆のタレ...なるほど、納豆のタレをベジマイトにしたらいいと思い...
The natto sauce... "We thought replacing the natto sauce with Vegemite would work..."
...マヨベースにして、その中にベジマイト入りタレを作りました。
"...so we made a mayo-based sauce and mixed Vegemite into it."
So, Vegemite is nice and salty, figured it could work as a base for a sauce...
"So, Vegemite is nice and salty. I figured it could work as a base for a sauce..."
...made a mayonnaise-based sauce and mixed Vegemite into it.
うまい。/ あ、うまい。/ 食えちゃうんだよね。
Delicious. / Yeah, it is. / You can actually eat it easily.
まあね。/ 美味しいです。This is so good, oh my god.
True. / It's delicious. This is so good, oh my god.
もう、キラキラ。/ へえ。/ 最後に行きますが。
I'm sparkling. / Wow. / Now, moving on to the final one...
何笑ってんのよ、お前。ん？
What are you laughing at? Huh?
何ヘラヘラしてんの、おい。
Why are you grinning like that?
食事後って、普段何食べております？
What do you usually eat after a meal?
あ、食事の後？うん、まあデザートみたいな。
Oh, after a meal? Well, usually something like dessert...
デザートですね！
Dessert, right!
次は僕が選んだ食べ物になります。We've reached the final dish.
Next is the food I chose. We've reached the final dish.
And normally at the end of every meal, you do have dessert. Australia's treasure!
二つを組んだらどうなるかちょっと...
What would happen if we combined these two...
宝物二つ？
Two treasures?
宝物二つを組んだらどうなっちゃうかちょっとめちゃくちゃ...
I was so curious about what would happen if we combined two treasures...
...気になったんで、最後の材料はこちらになります。
...so this is the final ingredient.
なに？怖。何、何？
What is it? I'm scared. What is it?
ティムタムです。/ 誰？
It's Tim Tam. / Who?
誰？誰、ティムタムは？/ その宝知らないわ。
Who? Who is Tim Tam? / I don't know that treasure.
誰、ティムタム？/ え？ティムタム知らないですか？
Who is Tim Tam? / Eh? You don't know Tim Tams?
知らないよ、ティムタム。
We don't know them.
え？これはオーストラリアのめちゃくちゃ有名なチョコレート、まあ、ビスケット、ウエハース...
Really? This is Australia's incredibly famous chocolate, well, biscuit, wafer...
あれ、あれ、ティムタムです。
...you know, Tim Tam.
ティムタムってお菓子ね。/ お菓子。
So Tim Tam is a snack. / Yes, a snack.
それをじゃあ、くれるんだ。その、ベジマイトとかじゃなくて、単体でね。
Oh, so you're giving us that. Just by itself, not with Vegemite.
嬉しいね。ありがたい。お土産でね。
That's nice. Thank you. A souvenir.
美味しいんだろうね。
I bet it's delicious.
そう、クッキー、ビスケットは。本当に呼んでくれてありがとう、今日は。
Right, a cookie or biscuit... Thanks for having us today.
ご褒美だよね、頑張った僕たちに対する。
It's like a reward for all our hard work.
ということで、ちょっとプロの方だったら、まあティムタムプラスベジマイト...
Well, actually, if it's a professional chef, they'll make Tim Tam plus Vegemite...
本当に、あの、美味しく
Truly, like, deliciously...
作ってくださるのかなって
...I wondered if they could make it tasty.
ちょっとお伺いしましたので。
That's why I asked them.
You know, it's a pro chef. I wanted to see what they could do. And I believe in their skills as a pro chef.
見ていきましょう！お願いします！
Let's take a look! Please!
ええ？！うわあ！
Eh?! Whoa!
え？おっとっと、どういうこと？
Eh? Wait, what does this mean?
ティラミス？
Tiramisu?
ティラミスじゃん！え、美味そう！どういうこと？
It's tiramisu! Eh, looks delicious! What do you mean?
まあ、ちょっと一旦、ベジマイト発案者だしさ
Well, since you're the one who brought Vegemite...
先に食べてみてよ。
...why don't you try it first?
はい、いただきます。
Okay, thank you for the food.
でもなんか、めちゃくちゃ美味しそう。
But it really looks incredibly delicious.
これがベジマイト入ってる？いただきます。
Is Vegemite really in this? Here I go.
いや、僕たちの警戒心が強くなりすぎてるだけかも。
Maybe we've just become way too cautious.
え？普通に美味しそう。
Huh? It looks normally delicious.
ティラミスじゃん。
It's just tiramisu.
いただきます。
Here I go.
あれ？本当にこれ入ってます？ベジマイト。
Huh? Is Vegemite really in here?
え？入ってそうですよ。
Eh? It seems like it is.
美味しい！
It's delicious!
え？本当にティラミスじゃん。
Eh? It's really just tiramisu.
普通にティラミス？いただきます！
Just normal tiramisu? Thank you for the food!
あれ？ベエちゃんが一番分かってないまである。
It might be that Bae-chan understands it the least.
マジで？ベジマイトがいるのか？
Seriously? Is Vegemite really in there?
かすかに塩味があって、うま！
There's a subtle saltiness, and it's delicious!
あ、いるわ！いる！いる！
Ah, it's there! It's there!
え、うま！めっちゃ美味いんだけどこれ！
Eh, delicious! This is incredibly tasty!
美味しい！Oh my god!
It's delicious! Oh my god!
これお店出しましょう。
Let's open a shop with this.
本当に！We need a copyright, patent, oh my god!
Really! We need a copyright, patent, oh my god!
すごい、ガチで美味い。
Amazing, it's seriously delicious.
ティムタムと合う料理を思いつくのが大変でした。
It was hard to think of a dish that goes with Tim Tams.
ティムタムは絶対コーヒーが合うと思ったので、ティラミスにしました。
I thought coffee would definitely go well, so I made tiramisu.
ティムタムのクッキーはサクサク感を活かしたいので、ティムタムを砕いてベジマイトを
To keep the crunchy texture of the Tim Tam cookies, I crushed them and soaked them in Vegemite...
染み込ませ... 染み込ませて
...soaked them...
砕いてその中にベジマイト入れて混ぜてそれをやってるんだ。
Ah, they crushed it, mixed Vegemite in, and did that!
So, apparently it was really hard to think of a dish that would pair well with Tim Tam. Um, but Tim Tam goes well with coffee. Decided to make a tiramisu. Also wanted to keep the crunchy texture of the Tim Tam, so I crushed it up, soaked it with Vegemite.
すっげえ、ベエちゃん！
That's amazing, Bae-chan!
しかも、普通のティラミスより美味しくなってて
Plus, it's actually tastier than normal tiramisu.
塩味が良い味出してる。
The saltiness brings out a great flavor.
甘みが際立つというか、
It highlights the sweetness, so to speak.
生クリームの濃さとかが塩味によって中和される感もあって、くどくない。
The richness of the cream is also neutralized by the salt, so it's not heavy.
ね！うまい！
Right?! Delicious!
コーヒーの香りと苦味で、ティムタムの
With the coffee's aroma and bitterness, the Tim Tam's...
すっごい甘い感じも程よくまろやかになって
...intense sweetness becomes pleasantly mellow.
ティムタムが美味いんじゃないの？
Isn't it just that Tim Tam is delicious?
でもティムタムの美味しさを
But elevating the deliciousness of Tim Tam...
昇華させたのもベジマイトのおかげなんで。
...is all thanks to Vegemite.
これ美味い！凄い。
This is delicious! Amazing.
プロって凄いな、あのベジマイトをこんなに。
Chefs are amazing, doing this with that Vegemite.
あのベジマイトはやめてください。
Please don't say "that Vegemite."
ごめんなさい。めっちゃ食ってますね。
I'm sorry. He's eating so much.
完食です！
I finished it!
全部美味かったな、今んとこ３個食べたけど。
All of them were delicious, out of the three we've eaten so far.
ちょっと最後に、美味しさっていうか、三ツ星の評価をやりたくて
Finally, I want to do a three-star rating.
I want to rate all of the different dishes.
どれが一番美味しいか決めたいので。
I want to decide which one is the most delicious.
今まで食べた中で、どれが一番ベジマイトと相性が良かったかってことね。
So, out of what we've eaten, which paired best with Vegemite.
じゃあまず、先輩の牛タンですね。
First, senpai's beef tongue.
How many stars are we giving the beef tongue?
俺は、二つ星かな。
For me, maybe two stars.
Two stars? 俺も二つかな。
Two stars? I think two as well.
僕も二つだと思います。めちゃくちゃ美味しかった。
I also think two stars. It was incredibly delicious.
次が、ハルさんの納豆ですね。
Next is Haru-san's natto.
一つ星かな。俺も一つ星かな。
Maybe one star. I think one star too.
自分は２.５なんですけど。めちゃくちゃ美味しい。
I would give it 2.5, though. It was delicious.
美味しかったけど、ベジマイトがいた。
It was delicious, but Vegemite was there.
主張しすぎてた。まだ恋しくなるくらいだった。
It was too strong. Still felt too present.
確かにそうですね。あれが好きだったかもしれない。
That's true. I might have liked that.
最後、僕のティラミス、ティムタム。
Lastly, my tiramisu Tim Tam.
三！
Three!
三！僕も三！勝った！三ツ星！
Three! Me too, three! We won! Three stars!
ベジマイトがティムタムの甘さを活かしてた。
Vegemite really brought out the Tim Tam's sweetness.
二つの宝が合わさることで、たった一つの大宝になってた。
By combining two treasures, they became one ultimate treasure.
こいつオーストラリアから何か貰おうとしてる。
This guy is trying to get something from Australia.
僕アニメ声優やってますんで。
I am an anime voice actor, after all.
美味しかった。
It was delicious.
すごく、企画、まあ、こういう感じだったんですけど、ちょっとベジマイトのあの最初のまあ、イメージ変わりました？
So we had this kind of plan, but did your first image of Vegemite change?
最初のイメージ変わりました？最初に食べてみてからと
Did your first impression change after trying it?
最初に食べてみて…
After trying it for the first time...
感想変わりました？もしかして
Maybe your impression has changed?
なんか物によってはというか こんなにもやり方次第で
Depending on how it's used, or rather, I was surprised
ベジマイトの味が変化していくものなのかとか
at how much the flavor of Vegemite can change.
色々な使い方があるんだな ていうのでびっくりはしたね
I was surprised to see there are so many different ways to use it.
うん すごくびっくりしました 僕は ベジマイト
Yeah, I was really surprised by Vegemite.
So Ougi-senpai shocked. 好きになりました？
So Ouga-senpai is shocked. Do you like it now?
はい？
Huh?
好きになりました？
Do you like it now?
はい！ありがとうございます。はい、ベジマイトが…
Yes! Thank you. Yes, Vegemite...
I like Vegemite.
いや、"like" じゃない。
No, not "like."
I love Vegemite.
あ、あざます。
Oh, thank you.
ありがとう。で、大治さんは？
Thank you. And what about you, Taiga-san?
俺は、やっぱりこう、最初の印象は、もういろんな味がすることでもう、なんというだろう、びっくりするな。
For me, my first impression was, because of all the different flavors, it was just... shocking.
みんなショックじゃん。
Everyone was shocked.
っていうなんか印象だったんだけど、こんなにいろんな調理の仕方すると
That was my impression, but cooking it in so many different ways
ベジマイトのそのいろんな味がするっていう良いところを、こう、ちょっとずつこう、拾っていけるんだと思って。
allows you to pick up on the good parts of Vegemite's complex flavors little by little.
無限の可能性がある食材だと、いう風に思いましたね。
I felt it's an ingredient with infinite possibilities.
好き？好きになりました？
Do you like it? Do you like it now?
あー、いや、まあ、ね。
Ah, well, you know...
あの、あんまり俺そう… 好きになりました？
I'm not really... Do you like it now?
Yes.
え？
What?
はい。
Yes.
え？好きになりました？
What? Do you like it now?
はい。
Yes.
あざます！
Thank you!
えっと、まあ、みんなもね、気になったらもう是非是非、ベジマイトを買って、自分でちょっとね、
So, if any of you are curious, please buy some Vegemite and try it yourselves,
自分の調理技術に自信があれば。
If you're confident in your cooking skills.
If you want to find your own ways to enjoy Vegemite, I feel like, you know, it will be such a great experience.
瓶はちょっと…
The jar itself is a bit...
まあまあ、何はともあれ、べーちゃん、本当に、マジで5周年おめでとう！
Well, anyway, Bae-chan, really... Happy 5th Anniversary!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ライブ開催もおめでとう！
And on hosting your live concert too, congratulations!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
Thank you to the two of them for coming. I can't believe this is how I'm celebrating my 5th year anniversary, but I'm so glad it is!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
じゃあ、せーの、
Now, ready, set...
おつベジマイトー！
Otsu-Begemite!
三つ星！
Three stars!
良い子は、真似しないで。
Kids, don't try this at home.
And with that, we're almost at the end of my anniversary stream!
I hope you all had fun today!
いや、もう、もう終わりたくないね！本当に5周年ありがとうございました。
No, I really don't want it to end! Thank you so much for five years.
Thank you so much for all the support of five years. We're not done yet!
まだね、お知らせ一個残ってます！なんと、グッズ、出ます！
We still have one more announcement left! And it is... merch is coming!
We still have our last announcement, 5th anniversary merch! We've got some really cool merch this time, too! Please check it out! Here!
Ah!
5th anniversary merch! Of course, it had to be the Monochrome Dancer and Rat Dancer.
This is the 'Best Oshi' merch. This beautiful artwork was done by Hyde-sensei. えっと、ハイド先生に描いていただきました！
This is the 'Best Oshi' merch. This beautiful artwork was done by Hyde-sensei. It was drawn by Hyde-sensei!
今回のグッズのテーマは、まあ、やっぱり、今年発表したモノクロームダンサー衣装と、バックダンサーの、まあ、お二人ですね。はい。
The theme for this merch is, of course, the Monochrome Dancer outfit revealed this year and her two back dancers.
Let's go through each item one by one! First up is this!
Ah!
First is the acrylic stand! 'Best Oshi' Acrylic Stand. ベストオシ、アクリルスタンドですね。
First is the acrylic stand! 'Best Oshi' Acrylic Stand.
It's so cool! It features the amazing artwork that Hyde did. And I think it features... it's all the best oshi.
まあ、ベストオシ、僕ですよね？僕ですね？僕ですね？はい。 Yes, of course.
Well, the best oshi is me, right? It's me, right? Yes, of course.
The best oshi, everyone's favorite oshi is me. But it does have the two back dancers in the back, because I know you guys love them.
I'm so obsessed with how it turned out. いや、めちゃめちゃかっこいい感じになったと思います！
I'm so obsessed with how it turned out. I think it turned out really cool!
Then, next up is...
Ah! The 'Rat Dancer' Jacket! Woohoo!
やっとですね！ Rat Dancer jacket is becoming official merch! グッズになりました！ジャケットが。
Finally! The Rat Dancer jacket is becoming official merch! The jacket is officially merch!
いや、本当に素晴らしい。 We've made a few adjustments so it's comfortable and easy to wear in everyday life.
It's truly wonderful. We've made a few adjustments so it's comfortable and easy to wear in everyday life.
ちょっとね、あの、このジャケットは着用しやすいよう、ちょっと調整をしたんですけど、本当にかっこいいジャケットになったと思います！
We made some adjustments so it's easier to wear, and I think it turned out to be a really cool jacket!
なんとね、あの、 this time, the 5th anniversary merch doesn't involve as many items, just because I know there's a lot happening. We've got the album, and also the live concert and everything.
And this time, the 5th anniversary merch doesn't have as many items, just because I know there's a lot happening. We've got the album, and also the live concert and everything.
So, it's only these two items, but if you pick up the complete merch set, you'll also get this!
You will get a replica sticker with a signature, and an exclusive ASMR voice pack as a special bonus. Thank you so much for always supporting me.
えっと、もしね、今回ちょっとね、あの、色、たくさん告知とお知らせがあったんですけど、
Even though there were so many announcements and updates this time,
で、今回の、こちらの、あの、5周年グッズは2点になります。
So, there are two items in this 5th Anniversary Set.
えっと、もしセット買ってくれた方に、えっと、複製サイン入りのステッカーとASMRボイスが特典で付いてきます！
If you buy the set, you'll get a duplicated autograph sticker and ASMR voice pack as a bonus!
The title of the voice pack is "Be my model."
Uh, we check out the sample of the Rat Downunder Jacket together,
We check out the sample of the Rat Downunder Jacket together,
and there's even a scene where we actually recorded using the real jacket sample. So I hope you'll give it a listen!
えっと、まぁこちらのボイスのタイトルは「ボクのモデルになって！」
The title of this voice pack is "Be my model!"
いや、先ほどね、あの、紹介した、えっと、ジャケットのサンプルを使って、
We actually used the jacket sample that I introduced earlier
一緒に何だか、あの、ボイスのシチュエーションを作ったっていうか、まぁ、あの、収録しました。
to record the voice pack situation together.
お恥ずかしながら、ぜひ聞いててください。
It's a bit embarrassing, but please give it a listen.
Uh, you can access the shop directly from YouTube, so be sure to check it out.
You can access the shop directly from YouTube, so be sure to check it out.
YouTubeからショップアクセスできるので、チェックしてください！
You can access the shop from YouTube, so please check it out!
That was the actual final announcement.
But before I go, there's one more thing I wanted to do with you all.
And in order to do that,
I need to first...
変身！
Transform!
アハハハハハ
Ahahaha!
はい、アイドルベェ来ました。
Alright, Idol Bae is here!
Uh, I just wanted to sing one song before we end today's stream.
I just wanted to sing one song before we end today's stream.
Um, I just want to say thank you so much for five years.
Thank you so much for five years.
I'll continue doing my best. Thank you so much for everything you've given me, and I will do my best.
まぁ、5年間本当にありがとうございました。
Truly, thank you so much for the past five years.
ちょっと最後にね、1曲歌いたいなと思ってます。
I wanted to sing one last song at the end.
気持ちを込めて、これからも頑張りたいと思いますので、最後に1曲聞いてください！
With all my heart, I will continue to do my best. Please listen to this final song!
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
誇り高きアイドル！
A proud idol!
私のこと知ってますか？可愛く見えてますか？
Do you know who I am? Do you think I look cute?
私の歌どうだろうな うまく歌えてますか？
What do you think about my singing? Did I manage to sing well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか 可愛く見えてますか？
My costume and make-up, do I look cute wearing them?
振付とかファンサとかも 喜んでもらえますか？
My dancing and my fanservice too, do they make you happy?
手は冷たくなって 足は震える
My hands are getting cold and my legs are shaking.
それでも戦いたい アイドルだから
Even so, I still wanted to keep on fighting, because I'm an idol.
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate the people who make fun of me.
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I don't like to be looked down on either.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を 見てもいないくせに言うな
And words like "idols are nothing," don't say them when you haven't even seen them!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my hard work for granted.
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force an image on me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
And words like "idols are nothing" are the one thing I hate the most in this world!
プライベート見えないから 分からないと思います
Because you can't see my private life, I don't think you'd know this side of me.
性格とか悪い方です 騙しちゃってますか？
My personality is actually pretty bad. Did I manage to fool you?
でも本気です本気なんです ありのままの私を
But it's the truth, I'm being serious. Please love me the way I am...
好きになって推して下さい それってワガママですか？
and become my fan. Is that a selfish thing to ask?
きっと可愛くない 全部分かってる
I'm sure that I'm not cute. I already knew it all.
それでも好かれてたい アイドルだから
Even so, I still wanted to be liked, because I'm an idol.
皮肉言う奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who say sarcastic things.
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
I hate people who keep making excuses too.
“こんなもんか”という言葉を 軽々しく口にするな
And words like "is that all?" don't just say them so lightly!
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't just set limits on me.
笑い者に なんてするな
Don't make a fool out of me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
And words like "idols are nothing" are the one thing I hate the most in this world!
向かい風を切り裂け
Cutting through the headwinds...
誇り高きアイドル
...a proud idol!
目指そうぜ
Let's aim to be one!
応援がなければ活動できない
Without all the support, I can't do any work.
好きな事ばかりじゃ生きてはいけない
I can't live my life by doing only the things that I like.
元気あげるはずが もらってばかりだし
Even though I'm supposed to give you energy, I continue to receive it instead.
恩返しできる日まで待ってて
Until the day I can repay you comes, wait for me!
待っててね！12月、約束だ！
Wait for me, okay? December, it's a promise!
歓声が減っても 飽きられちゃっても
Even if the cheers fade, or if people get tired of me,
それでも笑っていたい アイドルだから
I still want to keep smiling, because I'm an idol.
熱いファンの愛があって
With the love of my passionate fans,
スタッフさんの愛があって
with the love of the staff,
いつも家族の愛があって 生きてる
and with the love of my family always there... I live on!
アイドル！
As an idol!
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who make fun of us,
見下されるのも嫌いだ
and I hate being looked down upon.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を
Don't use words like "just an idol"...
見てもいないくせに言うな
...when you haven't even watched us!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take our hard work for granted,
イメージとか強制するな
and don't force your image on us.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
Words like "just an idol"...
この世で一番大嫌いだ
...are what I hate most in this world!
ありがとうねー！
Thank you so much!
MV見て！MV見て！
Watch the MV! Watch the MV!
Thank you everyone for being here!
Don't forget to check out YouTube Music Weekend right after this!
And also, give a lot of love to "I Found Me" MV!
このあとも見ててね！
Keep watching after this too!
がんばりカラー！がんばりカラー！応援して！よろしくお願いします！
Gambari Color! Gambari Color! Support me! Thank you so much!
Thank you so much for five years! I'll keep doing my best!
Bye bye!
Bye-bye!
[画面のテキスト]
After 5 years... I can finally say... MAMA I MADE IT
ほんとうに... ほんとうに... ありがとう♡
[On-screen text]
After 5 years... I can finally say... MAMA I MADE IT
Thank you so, so much... ♡